### Contact

+1(778)222-9295 (Mobile) karlovskaya@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ annakarlovskaya (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Web Development
Project Coordination
Operational Control

### Languages

English (Professional Working)
Russian (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Foundations of Project Management JavaScript: Understanding the Weird Parts

**Group Fitness Instructor** 

# Anna Karlovskaya

Tech-savvy Specialist with People Skills Coquitlam, British Columbia, Canada

# Summary

As a Front-End Developer I worked for a SaaS company in real estate business, eCommerce and a digital agency. Before that I worked in a well-known recruitment agency in Russia in operations, coordination and client relationship roles.

In free time I enjoy being with my family, meeting friends over a cup of tea or coffee, going to the sauna and gym, and volunteering. I am also a ACE certified Group Fitness Instructor with passion to get people moving. I love to dance, do yoga and strength workouts. I have Adult First Aid/CPR/AED certificate from American Red Cross valid till 4/22/25.

As a Front-End Developer I worked with:

- \* HTML, CSS (SASS/LESS), JavaScript, jQuery, PHP
- \* CMS: WordPress, Magento 1, 2
- \* UI Framework: Bootstrap
- \* JavaScript Frameworks: ReactJS, AngularJS 2 (basics)
- \* Adobe Suite: Illustrator, Photoshop, Adobe XD

Other technical skills and tools: mobile-first responsive design, Git, command-line user interface (Terminal), inVision, ticketing system (Jira, trello), Slack, Zoom.

As an Operation manager, Account manager and Project Coordinator my focus was on:

- \* Monitoring workflow and projects progress
- \* Preparing statistics and reports for upper management
- \* Supporting teams with following internal standards and procedures
- \* Working cross-functionally to ensure timely service delivery
- \* Documents and debt control monitoring

Tools: MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Google Docs, CRM platform

# Experience

*iMiracleProject* 

Operations Specialist (volunteer)

January 2023 - July 2023 (7 months)

Redmond, Washington, United States

Participate in various projects as a volunteer to help Ukrainian families.

#### **RESAAS**

Software Engineer (front-end)

December 2018 - December 2020 (2 years 1 month)

Vancouver, Canada Area

- Improved and maintained existing platform features
- Collaborated with the back-end team to ensure seamless integration between server and browser
- Participated in design reviews and code reviews
- Wrote unit tests, integration tests, UI tests

SoftwareKeep Group

Front-end Developer

November 2017 - November 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Vancouver, Canada Area

Magento is an open-source e-Commerce platform based on MVC architecture pattern and Zend framework.

- Built and updated custom modules to make front-end changes and enhancements on Magento 1 platform (5 websites and 12 store views)
- Developed responsive mobile-first promo and landing pages using PHTML, LESS/CSS/CSS3, jQuery
- Wrote, modified code using W3C and accessibility standards, validation tools
- Worked in collaboration with back-end developers, designers and marketing specialists

Weblnjected Solutions Inc.

Magento Front-End Developer

February 2017 - October 2017 (9 months)

Vancouver, Canada Area

- Customized Magento 2 themes layout and look and feel using LESS, XML, PHTML template files
- Developed responsive custom themes, landing pages using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery
- Searched, installed and customized third-party extensions

- Developed and implemented custom extensions
- Worked with designers to implement mockups with custom design
- Worked with project managers to understand project scope and objectives

#### Freelance

Web Designer

October 2016 - February 2017 (5 months)

Vancouver, Canada Area

Developed WordPress websites.

- Met with the client to determine requirements and goals, conducted regular client meetings for feedbacks
- Conducted content audit of current websites, competitive and gap analysis
- Updated content hierarchy and information architecture to meet client's needs
- Created paper wireframes and visual mockups for mobile and desktop website versions
- Developed using WordPress, conducted websites testing, client tutoring

### **BCIT**

Web Designer in Training
May 2016 - October 2016 (6 months)

During the 20-weeks course learned and practiced coding languages as well as mastering current web design technologies, UX Design best practices and SEO in challenging individual and group assignments.

- Developed responsive and well-structured websites from scratch using HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Photoshop and Illustrator
- Learned how to add interactivity with Javascript and jQuery and how to build dynamic websites with PHP
- Built customized websites on Wordpress using starter and child themes and various plugins
- Practiced building e-Commerce websites using WooCommerce and Easy Digital Download plugins

ANCOR Banking, Financial Services

4 years 6 months

**Operations Analyst** 

April 2012 - October 2014 (2 years 7 months)

Moscow, Russian Federation

Company provided recruitment and staffing services for banks and financial companies in Russia, Ukraine and Kazakhstan. Randstad Strategic Partner.

- Communicated with regional recruiters (18 colleagues in 7 branches in Russia and Ukraine) to monitor recruitment projects progress, provided recommendations, enforced internal standards and procedures
- Analyzed recruiting reports to improve recruiters' efficiency, prepared statistical reports for Operations Director and CEO
- Updated different client materials and databases, maintained intranet site,
- Created newsletters with industry news on regular basis
- Received recognition as "Most knowledgeable and always ready to help coworker" from colleagues and upper management

Account Manager May 2010 - April 2012 (2 years)

Reported to CEO, my client portfolio included 20 banks, insurance and leasing companies with extended retail branch network across Russia with 5 different HR products.

- Managed full projects cycle conducted negotiations, prepared commercial proposals, launched projects, projects implementation troubleshooting, debt control monitoring
- Communicated with other team members including Team and Product Leaders and recruiters to ensure timely and successful delivery services and meet target goals
- Prepared, analyzed and presented client reports and projects results to the team and upper management
- Successfully launched and completed more than 10 large cross-country projects for TOP 20 banks and financial companies that improved company brand recognition and customer loyalty

ANCOR Personnel Holding, Banks and Investment branch Regional Project Coordinator July 2008 - May 2010 (1 year 11 months) Moscow, Russian Federation

Company is one of the leaders in HR services in CIS market. Ten companies work under ANCOR brand and the group regional network includes over 40 offices.

- Coordinated recruitment projects for 25 clients in more than 30 cities across Russia
- Prepared invoices and tracked all client document circulation, worked in multi-disciplinary team (accountants, financial and legal specialists etc.)
- Advised and supported Moscow and remote recruiters to meet the organization's policies and procedures
- Rewarded as "Best Support Specialist"

# Education

British Columbia Institute of Technology
Certificate, Computing & Information Technology (2016)

Moscow State Technological University "Stankin" Master's in Economics and Management (GPA 3.64), Economics · (2003 - 2008)

School of Music "ROSINKA" Diploma, Piano Class · (1991 - 1998)